A Guide to the McLean Citizens Association Records, 1922-2014 [bulk]
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The McLean Citizens Association Records, 1922-2014 [bulk]
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 05-16
16.5 linear feet
McLean Citizens Association Records contains minutes, correspondence, reports, handbooks, promotional materials, clippings, photographs, and VHS tapes created and collected by the MCA spanning the years 1922-2014.
McLean Citizens Association
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by the McLean Citizens Association, Diane D’Arcy and Merrily Pierce in 1998, 1999, 2000 and later unknown dates.
Historical and Biographical Information
The McLean Citizens Association was founded in 1914 as the McLean School and Civic League. In 1953, the League was reincorporated as The McLean Citizens Association (MCA). Because McLean is an unincorporated community in Fairfax County, the MCA provides a forum where residents of the greater McLean area can address local issues and to advocate for solutions that serve the interests and values of the community. The MCA studies issues and advocates positions, sends representatives to task forces, hosts candidate debates, forums and town halls, and collaborates with elected officials and staff at all levels of government to accomplish its goals.
Scope and Content
McLean Citizens Association Records contains minutes, correspondence, reports, handbooks, promotional materials, clippings, photographs, and VHS tapes created and collected by the MCA spanning the years 1922-2014. The materials were collected by several different members and officers of the organization including Bayard Evans, Leighton Cain, Kay Sloan Burke, and Merrily Pierce. As such, the collection does not contain complete or comprehensive records of the MCA. The collection consists of administrative records, financial records, subject files, planning and zoning committee files, and records of related organizations including the Coalition to Save Evans Farm, McLean Community Center, and McLean Citizens Foundation.
Series 1: Administrative Records, 1953-2014, Undated, Boxes 1-7
This series contains administrative records of the MCA, including Constitution and By-Laws and Board of Directors handbooks, newspaper clippings, brochures, and photographs. It also includes materials, namely agenda, minutes, reports, and correspondence, related to both the Board of Directors and General Membership meetings. The McLean Letter, a newsletter sent to members, also contains agenda, meeting minutes, and reports.
Series 2: Financial Records, 1974-1996, Boxes 7-8
This series contains Reports of the Treasurer as well as bank statements, receipts, deposit slips, and other financial documents. Materials are arranged chronologically.
Series 3: Planning and Zoning Committee, 1950-2002, Undated, Boxes 8-22
This series contains records of the Planning and Zoning Committee, including meeting minutes, agenda, and notes, reports, correspondence, maps, and reference materials. The bulk of the series is comprised of files relating to individual rezoning, and other development applications in Fairfax County. These files include reports of the Department of Planning and Zoning; correspondence with Fairfax County, developers, and residents; architectural drawings, blueprints, and plats; meeting materials; clippings; and other documents. These files are arranged alphabetically by applicant.
Series 4: Subject Files, 1947-2003, Undated, Boxes 22-27
This series contains correspondence, reports, maps, drawings, and other materials on a variety of issues. Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Series 5: Related Organizations, 1964-2003
This series contains materials to organizations related to MCA, including the Coalition to Save Evans Farm, McLean Citizens Foundation, and McLean Community Center.
Sub-series 5-1: Coalition to Save Evans Farm, 1966-2003, Boxes 27-32
The Coalition to Save Evans Farm was a grass-roots citizens’ organization jointly sponsored by the MCA and McLean Broyhill Estates Civic Association in 1998 to preserve a 24 acre property formerly occupied by the Evans Farm Inn Restaurant. This series contains rezoning applications, correspondence, meeting minutes, fundraising and financial information, photographs, VHS tapes, stickers, and promotional materials.
Sub-series 5-2: McLean Citizens Foundation, 2001-2003, Undated, Box 32
The McLean Citizens Foundation (now known as McLean Community Foundation) was created by the MCA to fundraise and award grants for local projects. This series contains information relating to a grant awarded for the planting of trees at Haycock Elementary School as well as materials relating to the 20th anniversary of the founding of MCF. A photograph of past presidents of the MCA is also included.
Sub-series 5-3: McLean Community Center, 1964-1982, Boxes 32-33
The McLean Community Center was established by the MCA and other community organizations to provide facilities for civic, cultural, educational, recreational and social activities. This series contains by-laws, governing documents, meeting minutes, correspondence and other documents relating to the financing and construction of the MCC.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bayard D. Evans Collection, MSS 06-40; William J. “Bill” Elvin Collection, MSS 06-92
McLean Estates Civic Association Records, MSS 05-65
Index Terms
Burke, Kay Sloan; Cain, Leighton; Cities and Towns-Growth; City Planning; Coalition to Save Evans Farm; Dulles Toll Road (Va); Evans Farm Inn (McLean, Va.); Evans, Bayard; Fairfax County (Va) Board of Supervisors; Little League Baseball; Mclean (Va); McLean Community Center; McLean Community Foundation; McLean Legal; Pierce, Merrily; Richards, Lilla; Tysons Corner (Va); University of Virginia; Virginia Polytechnic Institute
Container List
- Series 1: Administrative Records, 1953-2014
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1972-1977, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Constitution and By-Laws--Other organizations (Little Hunting Creek Citizens Association, Hollinbrook Citizens Association, Somerville Hill Civic Association), Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors Handbook, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors Handbook, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors Handbook, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors Handbook, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors Handbook, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors Handbook, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors Handbook, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors Handbook, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Nomination of Officers and Directors, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Committee Member Directory, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Notice of Meetings, 1954-1964, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1953-1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1965-1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1992-1994 March (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1994 April-July (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1994 September-December (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1995 January (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1995 February (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1995 March (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1995 April (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1995 May (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1995 June (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1995 July (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1995 August (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1995 September (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1995 October (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1995 November (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1995 December (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes [photo], 1996 January (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1996 February (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1996 March (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1996 April (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1996 May (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1996 June (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1996 July (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1996 August (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1996 September (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1996 October (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1996 November (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1996 December (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1997 January (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1997 February (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1997 March (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1997 April (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1997 May-2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Meetings--Sign-in Sheets, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - McLean Letter, 1971-1976 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - McLean Letter, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - McLean Letter, 1980-1988 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Events--Citizen of the Year Banquet and Ceremony [photos], 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Events--85th Anniversary [photos], 1999 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Events--McLean Day [photos], 2006 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Events--Centennial Celebration, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - MCA Brochures, c. 1988-1999 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Series 2: Financial Records, 1974-1996
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1974-1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Receipts, Statements, etc., 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Receipts, Statements, etc., 1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Receipts, Statements, etc., 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Receipts, Statements, etc., 1994 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Receipts, Statements, etc., 1995 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Receipts, Statements, etc., 1996 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Deposit Slips, 1992-1996 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Balance Sheet, 1994-1996, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Series 3: Planning and Zoning Committee, 1950-2002
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1987-1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, Notes, 1991, Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Reports and Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Reports and Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Reports and Correspondence, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Reports and Correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Reference Materials, Undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Zoning, 1956-1959 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Zoning--Parking Ordinance, 1987-1993 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Zoning--Chesapeake Bay Preservation Ordinance, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Zoning--Chesapeake Bay Preservation Ordinance, 1992, Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Zoning--Proposed Zoning Ordinance Amendments, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Zoning--Board of Zoning Appeals Variances, 1991, Undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Zoning--Commerical and Industrial District Zoning, 1992, Undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Zoning--Proposed County Code Amendments, 1995, Undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Zoning--Proposed Zoning Ordinance--Service Station/Mini-Mart, 1996, Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Draft Tysons Corner Urban Center Plan, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Notice of Plans Filed, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 8180 Greensboro Associates (SE 89-D-052), 1989 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Amick (RZ 90-D-027), 1990 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Amoco/Chain Bridge (SE 87-D-088), 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Amoco/Leesburg Pike (SE 87-P-073), 1987 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Beaufort Park Association (RZ 86-D-006), 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Bell Atlantic Corporation (SE 97-D-020), 1997 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Bell Atlantic Mobile Systems (SE 80-D-045), 1993-1994, Undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Beverly/Rucker (RZ 85-D-039), 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Booth (RZ 93-D-039), 1994 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Boston (RZ 89-D-083), 1990, Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Boyce (RZ 87-D-044), 1987-1991 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Busby (RZ 85-D-107), 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Campbell (RZ 89-D-005), 1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Carwash on Leesburg Pike (SE 88-D-042), 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Chevron U.S.A. (SE 89-D-044), 1989 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Chevy Chase Bank (SE 94-D-019), 1994 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Choe (SE 92-D-018), 1992 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Church Diocese of Newton for the Melkites in the United States of America (SPA 80-D-069), 1998 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Clover Tysons (CA 86-D-085), 1989 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Condon Manor (RZ 92-D-017), 1992 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Coppola/Tyson's (SE 87-P-121), 1987 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Crown Central Petroleum (SE 87-D-110), 1987 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Design Management Group (SEA 83-D-041/042), 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Design Management Group (SE 88-D-095/096), 1988-1989, Undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Duffus/The Brooksfield School (SPA 87-D-051-2), 1996 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Eagle (AF 89-D-001), 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Eagle (AF 91-D-006), 1973-1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Edgemoor Homes (RZ 98-D-035), 1998 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Elm Street, 1999, Undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Esquire Group (RZ 89-D-057), 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Fairfax County Water Authority (SE 87-D-061), 1987 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Fire Station at Beulah Road and Route 7 (456-C89-31), 1989 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - First Virginia Bank (SE 93-D-003), 1993 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Fletcher (C-322/74-3-161), 1971-1986, Undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Foster (AF 90-D-002), 1990 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Frasca (SP 87-D-082), 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Freeborn/Jewett (AF 90-D-003), 1990 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Gannett (RZ 88-D-005), 1990-1994 June (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Gannett (RZ 88-D-005), 1994 July-September (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Gannett (RZ 88-D-005), 1994 October 3-19 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Gannett (RZ 88-D-005), 1994 October 20-31 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Gannett (RZ 88-D-005), 1994 November -1995 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Gannett (RZ 88-D-005), Undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Garfield Park, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Gasch (AF 91-D-004), 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - General Associates (SE 90-D-016), 1990 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Georgetown Pike Corner Partnership (RZ 94-D-040), 1994 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - GFS Realty/Giant Shopping Center, 1993-1998, Undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - GKG (PCA 85-D-081), 1991-1992, Undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Goodridge Drive Associates (SE 89-D-042), 1989 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Hadid (VC 88-D-027), 1988 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Heily (AF 87-D-002), 1987 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Hill's Plant Nursery (AF 91-D-008), 1992 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Holladay Property Services (RZ/FDP 1997-DR-021), 1998 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Hunting Ridge Associates (RZ/FDP 96-P-009), 1996-1997 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Immanuel Presbyterian Church (SEA 85-D-007), 1992 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Issa (SE 87-D-076), 1987 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Jarvis (SE 88-D-103), 1988-1991, Undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Karloid (SE 85-D-142), 1985-1986, Undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Kent Gardens Recreation Club (SPA 79-D-066), 1998 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Keplinger Addition to Nursery (SE 87-D-029), 1987 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Kim (SE 87-D-105), 1987 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Kontzias (RZ 90-D-034), 1990 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - L'Ambiance (Plan 9004-P-01) (1/2), 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - L'Ambiance (Plan 9004-P-01) (2/2), 1994-1996 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - L'Ambiance--Zimmerman (RZ 93-D-035) (1/4), 1993-1994 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - L'Ambiance--Zimmerman (RZ 93-D-035) (2/4), 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - L'Ambiance--Zimmerman (RZ 93-D-035) (3/4), 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - L'Ambiance--Zimmerman (RZ 93-D-035) (4/4), 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Langley Exxon, 1982-1993, Undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Langley School (SEA 84-D-086), 1989 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Langley School (VC 90-D-056), 1990 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Leesburg Pike (SEA 77-C-216), 1987 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Lewinsville Triangle Annual Plan Review, 1981-1984 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Lincoln Tysons (SE 87-D-059), 1987 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Lutheran Evangelical Church of the Redeemer (VC 98-D-012), 1998 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Madeira School (EA 83-D-030), 1989 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Madison Homes (RZ/FDP 1997-DR-048), 1996-1998, Undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Magruder & DiBenedetto (SE 91-D-021), 1993-1996 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Magruder & DiBenedetto (SEA 86-D-080), 1989 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - McAteer (SE 88-D-030), 1988 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - McElm Associates (SE 91-D-029), 1991 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - McLean Post 8241 Veterans of Foreign Wars (SEA-D-054), 1989 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - McLean Presbyterian Church (RZ 96-D-016), 1987-1996 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - McLean Square, 1989-1990, Undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - McLean Square Shopping Center (Site Plan 7975-SP-0201), 1995 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - McLean Tennyson (VC 88-D-155), 1988-1989 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - McLean Valley Estates (Plan # 3658-SD-01-2), 1950-1995 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - McLean Valley Estates (Plan # 3658-SD-01-2), 1996 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - McLean Valley Estates (Plan # 3658-SD-01-2), 1997 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Miller and Smith--Gates at Westfalls (RZ 82-D-023), 1988-1989, Undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Mobil Oil (SEA 84-D-100), 1990 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Mobil Oil (SEA 85-D-066), 1994 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Moon/Lee (VC 090-D-030), 1990 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Moutoux Orchard (AF 84-D-005), 1992 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Murnan (RZ 90-D-011), 1990-1997, Undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Nikzad McLean (SE 89-D-036), 1989 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Nys/Leonard (PCA 88-D-010), 1984-1993, Undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Odrick's Corner Interchange with DAAR, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Peacock Buick (SEA 77-D-201-1), 1987 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Potomac School (SEA 85-D-097), 1991-1997 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Potomac School (SEA 85-D-097), 1998-1999 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Potomac Vegetable Farm (AF 84-D-006), 1992 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Pozez (RZ 93-D-030), 1980-1994, Undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Prestige Partnership (RZ 87-D-079), 1987-1988 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Rev. John R. Keating/Youth Apostles Institute St. John's Catholic Church (RZ 95-D-040/SP 95-D-044), 1995 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Rosenthal (SEA 79-C-007), 1987 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Rucker, 1996-1999 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - S&J Associates (RZ 83-D-050), 1989-1990, Undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Schnider (Site Plan 7664-SP-01-2), 1989 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Schusterman (SE 89-D-049), 1989-1992 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Sheraton (RZ 80-C-072), 1981-1986, Undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Small Rent a Car (SE 87-D-066), 1984-1988, Undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Solitaire (6673-SD01-1), 1986-1988, Undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Stohlman's (SEA 82-C-077), 1987 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Sun Company (SE 95-D-048), 1995 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Ter-Minassian (VC 87-D-164), 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Termini (SEA 81-D-010), 1987 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Trustees of Temple Rodef Shalom (RZ 1997-DR-028/SE 97-D-038/RZ 2001-DR-013), 1998-2001 August (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Trustees of Temple Rodef Shalom (RZ 1997-DR-028/SE 97-D-038/RZ 2001-DR-013), 2001 Septepmber-2002, Undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Tycon (SEA 83-P-045), 1987 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Tyson's Cloverleaf (RZ 85-D-059), 1986 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Tysons Cloverleaf (RZ 87-D-080), 1987 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Tysons Cloverleaf (RZ 87-D-080), 1988-1990 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Tysons II Land Company (PCA/FDPA 84-D-049), 1995 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - University of Virginia/Virginia Tech Education Center/West Falls Church Transit Station Area--Chronology, 1975-1995 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - University of Virginia/Virginia Tech Education Center/West Falls Church Transit Station Area--Consultant Services for Metro Station Areas Study: West Falls Church Metro Station Area Study, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - University of Virginia/Virginia Tech Education Center/West Falls Church Transit Station Area (RZ 87-D-078), 1987 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - University of Virginia/Virginia Tech Education Center/West Falls Church Transit Station Area--Miller and Smith (RZ 82-D-024), 1988-1990, Undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - University of Virginia/Virginia Tech Education Center/West Falls Church Transit Station Area (RZ 95-D-005/SE 95-D-005), 1992-1994 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - University of Virginia/Virginia Tech Education Center/West Falls Church Transit Station Area (S 94-II-M1), 1988-1994 March (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - University of Virginia/Virginia Tech Education Center/West Falls Church Transit Station Area (S 94-II-M1), 1995 April-August, Undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - University of Virginia/Virginia Tech Education Center/West Falls Church Transit Station Area (RZ 95-D-005/SE 95-D-005), 1995 January-March (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - University of Virginia/Virginia Tech Education Center/West Falls Church Transit Station Area (RZ 95-D-005/SE 95-D-005), 1995 April-June (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - University of Virginia/Virginia Tech Education Center/West Falls Church Transit Station Area (RZ 95-D-005/SE 95-D-005), 1995 July, Undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Vega Investment Corp (RZ 83-D-027), 1983-1998 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Electric and Power Company (SE 86-D-071), 1986-1989, Undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - West Falls Church Metro Station, 1997-1998 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - West*Mac Associates (PCA 88-D-005), 1988-1995 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - West*Mac Associates (RZ 88-D-005), 1990 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - West*Mac Associates (RZ 88-D-005), 1991-1993, Undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - West*Mac Associates (RZ 95-P-011), 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - West*Park Associates (RZ 88-D-007), 1988 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - West*Park Associates (RZ 88-D-008), 1988 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Whelan/Small (DA 81-D-024), 1989 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Wilheim (VC 88-D-033), 1988 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Williams/Thompson (RZ 86-D-116/RZ 87-D-017), 1986-1987, Undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Young (SE 87-D-123), 1987 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Younkman, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Series 4: Subject Files, 1947-2003
  - Baseball Stadium, 1991, Undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Broyhill Estates Property, 1964-1982 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Central Intelligence Agency Master Plan, 1998-1999, Undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Chesterbrook Affordable Assisted Living Facility, 2000-2001 August (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Chesterbrook Affordable Assisted Living Facility, 2001 September -2002 February (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Chesterbrook Affordable Assisted Living Facility, 2002 March-2003, Undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - "Comprehensive Plan McLean Planning District," Division of Planning, County of Fairfax, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Control Data Property, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence and Notes, 1956-1960, Undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and Notes, 1973-1982, Undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and Notes, 1989-1994 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Department of Environmental Mangement, 1994-1998 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Disney America, 1993-1994, Undated (Box 23, Folder 5)